A Guide to the Dabney Family Ledger and Papers, 1755-1868 (bulk 1755-1778)
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Dabney Family Ledger and Papers 1755-1788, 1755-1868
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 79.1
18 items.
Dabney Family,; Charles Dabney, 1745-1829,; William Dabney, 1707-1772?
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1979.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm (M-1585)
Biographical/Historical Information
William Dabney, of Hanover County, Va., served as steward for Edward Ambler, Dudley Digges, and Armistead Lightfoot.
Scope and Content Information
Ledger contains plantation accounts of William Dabney (1707-1772?) of Hanover County, Va., and blacksmith accounts of his son, Charles (1745-1829). Entries provide information on crops and slaves as well as recording payments for services such as carpentry, shoemaking, and midwifery. Collection also includes seventeen loose pieces, primarily accounts.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Dabney family.
Persons:
Ambler, Edward, 1733-1768.; Dabney, Charles, 1745- 1829.; Dabney, William, 1707-1772?; Digges, Dudley, 1718-1790.; Lightfoot, Armistead, 1730-1771.
Subjects:
African Americans-- Clothing--Virginia--History--18th century--Sources.; African Americans--Employment--Virginia--History--18th century-- Sources.; Carpentry--Virginia--History--18th century--Sources.; Midwives--Virginia--History--18th century--Sources.; Shoemakers--Virginia--History--18th century--Sources.; Slavery--Virginia--History--18th century--Sources.; Tobacco--Virginia--History--18th century--Sources.; Wheat--Virginia--History--18th century--Sources.
Contents List
- Ledger, 1755-1778.
- Account. Itemized, n.d.
- Portion of printed map showing Fort Fenny and vicinity, n.d.
- Account. Col. Dudley Diggs. Itemized. verso--Williamsburg, Mr. John Winston, Mr. Robert Donald, and Mr. John Chiswell, 15 October 1753-22 February 1754.
- Account. Stephen Pettus, Jr. Itemized, 1755-1758.
- Account. Col. Dudley Digges to Pouncey Anderson. For smith's work (itemized), 14 July 1755-20 February.
- Account. Capt. William Dabney [and E. Ambler?] Itemized, September 1755-5 June 1756.
- Account. Col. Dudley Diggs. Itemized, 14 September-15 December 1755.
- Document. Pouncey Anderson and Christo[phe]r Benny[ms?]. re: weighing a stray hog at Col. Dudley Diggs' plantation at William Dabney's request, 13 December 1755.
- Receipt. Buchanan & McDouall to Col. Dudley Diggs. For salt, cloth, and tacks, March 1758.
- Account. Louisa Co. Capt. William Dabney to Joseph Holt. For shoes--women's, men's, children's, and Negroes' (itemized), 20 June 1758-8 October.
- Account. Capt. William Dabney to William Farthing. Itemized. For making "Negroe shoes." 0ctober 1758.
- Account. Capt. William Dabney re medical supplies and treatment. Includes midwives' fees for Bridget and Ann, 1760-1761.
- Account. Capt. William Dabney for Col. Diggs. Itemized, 19 May 1760-1 December.
- Accounts. [?] to Richard Anderson, Christo. Wood, Mr. Ambler, Thomas Swiss, and John Robinson, Esq. Itemized, 1761-1762.
- Letter. William Lane to Capt. William Dabney of Hanover. Request to pay George Pettus 14s current money. Figuring of accounts to James Turner, Mr. Morris, and P. Timberlake on verso 1 January 1762.
- Account. Mrs. Sarah Winston to William Pollard. Itemized. Court costs. Verso--Col. Dabney to pay, January 1764-August.
- Richmond. Letter to Charles W. Dabney. Offers his services as a commission merchant; quotes prices for tobacco, corn, oats, rye, and wheat, 16 May 1868.